hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is Jeremy
Krakowski and I'm so excited that you're
listening today I want to share with you
some of my experiences that have helped
me in my business and for those of you
that haven't met me yet my name is
Jeremiah grakowski I've been helping
coaches trainers mentors speakers
authors people that have a message or
people that are just starting out they
feel a desire to coach people and
they're growing and they want to build a
business around their message I help
them make six seven and even eight
figures in their business if they're
going from zero brand new I give them a
framework to make six figures once
they're making six figures I show them
how to scale that the systems needed to
scale that and then how to take that
seven figure income and amplify it
either even further and so today I'm
just so excited to share with you some
of what has helped me so much in the
this journey I've worked with a number
of clients thousands of clients over the
years and I've learned a few things that
have radically shifted my life that have
shifted my relationships but most
importantly they have increased the
amount of income that I can make in my
business and that's why I'm sharing it
with you on this podcast is because I
actually believe that this one strategy
that I'm going to give you today by the
end of this will have a dramatic shift
in your income earning potential how
much you can make and it's it's actually
something that you can start doing right
away but it is a practice that might
take you a little while to master it's
taken me uh about about two years to
really start to figure it out I get a
little bit better each day a little bit
better each week and then I noticed
areas where I struggle with it last week
I struggled with it but by really having
this in our mind this practice is going
to help you okay and so this is what it
is is
as a coach as a trainer
as somebody that's a mentor if you're
somebody that's an expert in anything or
you've been a leader
we can notice where other people are
going wrong or what they're doing wrong
or the mistakes they're making and we
want to help them and we have a desire
to help other people
um
but there comes an appropriate time to
do that
when you first meet somebody
if that person isn't coming to you
specifically asking you to help them no
matter how helpful we think we're being
criticizing other people
telling them what they're doing wrong
pointing out their flaws
is not a helpful way to communicate with
people
and and and
and
at the risk of me even being judgmental
saying this I'm just going to share this
in my life is I was somebody that that I
always wanted to help people and I could
always see and point out what they
needed to do right what they needed to
change
I always could see the mistakes that
everybody made I always saw my mistakes
and I grew up where my safety security
happiness and hope in my life was built
around being able to quickly identify
what I'm doing wrong and fix it and
quickly identify what others are doing
wrong and fix it and in this this became
a framework of how I was living my life
in every single relationship every
single business experience I was in I
would
build it around pointing out what
everyone's doing wrong
and
I wondered why I noticed something was
happening
and this is what made the shift in me
to where I actually stopped doing this I
actually to this day as as much as
possible right because we're human we
all make mistakes it's impossible not to
make mistakes
by a accepting that and and and B
becoming okay with our own mistakes
and realizing that we don't have to be
perfect that it's okay if we're not
perfect and then nobody else needs to be
perfect that one Foundation
and then making the intentional choice
that even if I see somebody making a
mistake
doing something wrong
not doing what they should
My First Response isn't to point it out
to them
to let them know what they need to be
doing right
my first response is to honor to accept
to listen and to learn
and to come from a place of compassion
not criticism not thinking that I know
what's best for this person and so that
I need to change them into what I think
they need to be
that I need to make sure that they do
the right thing that I need to come
alongside them and help them stay on the
straight and narrow that I need to come
alongside them and show them where
they've erred in their ways
and and I grew up in a in a church that
taught me
that that was my job as a person was to
point out where everybody was wrong that
that to help other people was to always
say well this is what you're doing wrong
and that's what you should be doing
right and I ended up bringing that into
business I was pointing out typos on
people's websites and I would I would
write companies and tell them what they
were wrong and I would say okay this is
an issue you're probably losing business
around this but here's the thing
I never seem to get a response back
I never seem to have anybody give me
feedback back
and I wondered why does it seem that
every time I do this I'm being so
helpful to people
I'm being so helpful I have such Amazing
Ideas that can help them
but they didn't want my help
and and I actually sought out a mentor
on this
I actually directly asked my mentor this
question
and what he told me was is that
correction in any form
whether it be in business whether it be
a typo and a website
telling somebody the mistakes they make
pointing out their mistakes
only comes
when somebody is in connection with you
has trust and these are the and this is
the third one that's most important
they have connection with you they have
trust
and they've actually sought you out to
be the person to show them what they're
doing wrong
and that third one was really important
for me because I'm like I can see what
people are doing wrong
I can always see that
but
if they haven't asked me to give
feedback if they haven't sought me out
for feedback
it was only feeding my own ego
to do that and it was validating my
story that nobody cares what I what I
think
and so I was constantly seeking
validation I was constantly seeking
approval from other people based off of
how I would criticize
how I would point out the errors in
other people's ways
and and this became a cycle in my life
until I stopped doing this and I'm
telling you
like
night and day
every relationship I was losing business
deals because of this and the business
deals started flooding in as soon as I
stopped doing this
the money started flooding in
and you know I had this belief that well
I'm sacrificing somebody's future for my
own personal gain
I had this false humility where I was
like well I'm gonna point out what they
do wrong to save them from destruction
even if it means it's gonna cost me
money
and I had this vigilante like superhero
type complex where I was the one the
Savior that was gonna swoop in and show
everybody the air of their ways and what
they needed to do right and I had to
actually lay that down that became an
idol in my life that became something
that I worshiped was my ability to point
out what everybody was doing wrong my
ability to be so accurate
with that in people
and I wondered and in that season when I
was doing that I wondered why I was
struggling to grow my business
and here's what ended up happening
my own judgment of other people ended up
coming back at me my own judgment of
other people's wrong doings and when I
talk about wrongdoings again I'm talking
about
the color on their website like like
we're not talking about
violent issues here
we're not talking about robbing stealing
killing and destroying anybody that's
not what I'm talking about okay
we're not talking about if we're if
we're speaking like from a from a
spiritual or religious perspective like
a a sin of some kind right like I'm not
talking about that and and I even to
this day I think that
that I can speak truth in certain
situations but I'm not going to go out
there and tell everybody you are doing
wrong and you should be doing right
because they haven't sought me out for
that I believe that we actually take
away from other people
the ability to learn themselves and we
end up stepping into codependency which
is an addictive toxic relationship style
where we end up making ourselves the
savior of other people we're saying well
if I didn't help them they would hurt
themselves
it's a great book on this topic called
codependent no more
that really helps with this codependent
no more it's written by Melody Beatty
and it's all about reverting the
patterns that we have in our lives
caring for other people
caring for ourselves making that better
setting powerful boundaries
and not allowing
the need to control other people
take over us how to start focusing on
ourselves and becoming in a healthy way
more selfish
unless on looking at what others are
doing wrong
and when I started doing this in my life
when I started doing what I wanted to do
and I stopped looking at what everyone
else is doing wrong and wanting them to
do what was right and wanting to make
sure that everybody I worked with here's
the thing that's not a healthy way to
coach that's not a healthy way to lead
that's based off of control
and that's based off of
um really some very toxic
old unhealthy uh ineffective
ways of being and serving people is when
we when we believe that we're supposed
to
swoop in to rescue somebody and that
that that we're so focused on what other
people are doing
as a coach you're gonna be focused on
your clients they've paid you to point
out what they need to change when I make
this podcast I'm thinking about people
that listen to this podcast that have
come to me for advice that trust my
advice and my wisdom
and so I have Avenues where I share that
and I'm very even careful on how I do
that you notice in this podcast episode
I don't want anyone to feel like doing
this is a bad thing
or or a wrong thing I don't want guilt
and shame to get into anybody's life
guilt and shame
don't help us at all
we just haven't been taught a better way
I was never taught a better way I was
taught growing up that it was my
responsibility to take care of
everything and to make sure to to do all
the right things that make sure that
people do all the right things and it
was my job to manage and maintain other
people's emotions and feelings it's not
by the same token it's also not our job
to try to make anybody do what we think
they should it's not our job to force
our will opinion or version of how we
think other people should be living
their life on them
and this is something powerful powerful
powerful that when I started to
understand this when I really got this
when I really stepped into a place of
giving up
being codependent with other people
giving up feeling like I had to be the
savior of everybody even though I could
see
I'm gonna be super honest with you I
literally everybody who comes into my
space I can see exactly what they need
to do
to make more money
but it's not always the time and place
to tell them
and I used to think that I wasn't
serving people well that I was doing
them a disservice to not tell them this
and the truth is that by me actually
holding back
I was helping them more in the way they
really needed to be helped
by me building my business and focusing
on how can I attract the right customers
that I was helping the right people and
attracting the people that really had
ears to hear here's the truth when I
make a podcast episode like this there
might be a small group of people that
might get upset or offended by it and
never listen to a thing I say again and
that's great
that's awesome
it's not my job to make sure that other
people
do the right thing it's not my job to
make sure that anybody
does what they should even as a coach
it's my job to provide an opportunity
to provide accountability and to ask the
Strategic questions what have you done
and then to point out and when they come
to me and say hey what can I do better
now I can give my opinion
now I give my thoughts
now of course on my social media all day
long I'm putting my opinion out there
constantly
it's part of it
but I'm not directly coming to people
and saying you should be doing this
you should be doing this
and I found that that created a safe
space for other people to have an
opportunity to grow
for people to have an opportunity to
step out a step up is if I spoke truth I
had a lady uh the other week come to me
and say you know I'm struggling with a
lot of fear a lot of worry what would
you say Jeremiah and I'm telling you I
did I wrote a novel on what she could do
and I made a 30 minute video
and she wrote me and said that was so
powerful that's exactly what I needed
because she had asked for that
information but if I had just came at
her and was like you need to do this
this is what you're doing wrong it's not
serving her
and as a coach
it's our job to serve people the way
that they want to be served not the way
that we want for them
people are paying you for a result
when they hire you as a coach and this
is where in coaching we get this mixed
up but they're paying me for a result
this is the result right here
and this is what they're doing
and they're disconnected right here
sometimes beginning coaches end up
believing that it's their job to bridge
this Gap
it's not
it's not at all
that's called being codependent
that's called controlling others
and part of it could be we're afraid
that our integrity will be brought into
question
if I can't make a result for them now do
I have the Integrity to say that I can
help that person right
and we end up going on this cycle and
there's even some really
um I believe
unhealthy coaching training out there
that tells people that they should force
and pressure people into doing actions
and and and Hound people down and do
that and become codependent and make
people take action I'm here to say
here's the thing
you're not going to make any money that
way because here's the thing is that if
you do that you're stepping into What's
called the corporate mindset with people
okay
to where now it's the boss's
responsibility to make the employee do
what they're supposed to do you end up
stepping into a boss
employee
relationship
when you're trying to fill the Gap right
here to where now the cochi
and their results are contingent on the
boss
micromanaging them and making sure
they're doing what they should
and that's not sustainable that's not a
way to build a coaching business that
will breed resentment
it doesn't produce long-term lasting
results because here's the thing as a
coach
what you want is you want people to make
one of two decisions
to either take action on their own
or to leave your space
to no longer work with you anymore
and we have to be willing to let go of
people we have to be willing to have a
an open hand
to where we're not trying to
make people do what we think they should
that we're not trying to hold on so
tightly
to people
to make sure that they're on the
straight and narrow that we give them
the opportunity to step up rise up take
responsibility on their own and decide
am I going to take action of my own or
am I going to blame and not take
personal responsibility
as a coach it's our job to call people
up to
personal
responsibility
otherwise we end up stepping into a
toxic codependent relationship
where we are now responsible for the
other person's result
as a coach I'm responsible for
presenting opportunities giving guidance
and pointing people in the right
direction when they ask for it
I'm not responsible for them taking
action
and neither are you
you're not responsible for making sure
that anybody does what they should
and when we give up that
crown that responsibility
it allows for some really amazing
beautiful things to happen
it allows for some really incredible
opportunities for growth for
conversation
because now it's no longer a dictator
relationship
of submission and Authority
rather
it's a place of mutual respect
it's a place of saying I'm going to do
my part but I expect you to do your part
and anybody who coaches with me I expect
them to do their part
it's not my job to make sure that they
do and that allows me to be a better
Coach to serve more people and my own
mental energy here's the truth my mental
energy as a coach doesn't have the
capacity
to make sure to hold everybody to do
what they should
I've tried that it'll make you go crazy
it'll make you go insane
always doing that
but there's ways to be more effective
at getting people to do the best thing
in their business and the best thing in
there in their career and their job and
their Fitness and their spirituality and
all that
see this is what I'm talking about here
this this episode is all about being
effective
the most effective way
to bring change in other people's lives
is by not criticizing people
by not
fault finding
by not pointing out
mistakes
it's actually the most effective way to
lead people
is by not doing this but rather coming
from a lens of compassion
understanding
and and really
going and working with those that want
your help
that want you to give
feedback wisdom advice and then sharing
it with those people oftentimes
beginning coaches we may feel like well
I have so much I can bring to the table
yet nobody's wanting me to help them
so you want to find some people
that are actually looking for you to
bring wisdom for them instead of going
out there and coaching everybody you
meet instead of coaching every single
person out there that you meet
I have a lot of friends and people in my
life that I we don't have a relationship
where I I am I coach them because that's
not what our relationship is built on
and it's a very healthy relationship and
I don't do any of this and even those
that I do coach I'm still not going to
do this
that's the key
until
they come to me and ask for some advice
and wisdom that's why I give
opportunities to ask questions
constantly
and so when you provide opportunities
for people to ask questions
oh here's something I even forgot I I
completely forgot
so when I was starting my coaching
business
I
got frustrated that nobody was asking me
for help nobody was asking for my wisdom
I had so much to offer people and nobody
was coming to me actually asking how I
could help them and I frustrated me and
I realized that it was because I hadn't
created a safe space for people to do
that without feeling judged by me
without feeling like I was pointing out
what they were doing wrong
and listen it's not helpful to say oh
I'm not criticizing you oh I'm just
trying to help you
what you're just trying to do and how
they're perceiving it
are two very different things and so we
got to be aware of that is no matter
what your intention is how it comes
across to people is as criticism
and so when we can choose to to to
create a safe space where people can ask
questions where we're not trying to make
anybody be molded to what we want them
to be and instead we allow them to
flourish in their best version of
themselves possible
even if that means ignoring fault
ignoring what we want to point out as
wrongdoing
it allows us an opportunity to build the
most important thing with people and
that is Trust
when trust is built
the game flips
when I have trust with somebody
and they are asking me a question to
give feedback I had a guy on my live
call yesterday I spent about 30 minutes
working with him through something that
I
felt was not a good idea for his
business
but he had come to me for that and I
could tell I was building trust in that
and he got it he understood what I was
trying to share
because I didn't make my desire for him
to know what I see most important I made
just coming from understanding
compassion and listening my priority
and so then that allowed me to speak
into what was helpful for him and
appoint him in a very unique direction
that I've actually never helped coach
anybody on before it was in an area that
I don't even have experience and I told
him I don't have any experience in this
area here's something that I'm feeling
that maybe you want to check out and he
was like wow that's pretty good good
idea because we were able to unpack that
together
and I said it you might struggle with
this
when we learn how to communicate and how
to connect with people more effectively
by building trust by coming from a place
of compassion and not trying to make
sure that people do what they should
opportunities for being more effective
to help other people arise far more than
just being helpful
and and truthfully I identified as sort
of a it's it's a bit of a childish thing
is what it is is wanting to tell
everybody what they're doing wrong
because we don't feel like we're heard
we're trying to validate ourselves
there's an inner child and this isn't a
bad thing this childish thing there's an
inner child I believe in all of us that
was wounded that was hurt and we're
trying to allow that child to come
forward when you allow space for your
inner child to speak and to feel safe
you become the most effective person the
most effective version of yourself but
when it's stuffed down we end up doing
things like blurting out our opinions
blasting people with what they should do
criticizing trying to be overly helpful
with people
and it creates the opposite effect and
it ends up repeating
scenarios in our life that validate that
weed are that our opinions don't matter
you get it you ever felt like your
opinions don't matter you ever felt like
people don't listen to your opinion you
ever felt like nobody cares what you had
to say
it's because we end up doing this and
we're trying to make sure that people
hear us I was one of those people
I used to do that
because I felt like nobody listened to
me about anything
until I started operating in this
framework
until I stopped criticizing stopped
trying to make people do what they
should point out their wrongdoings and I
started to become more effective at
coaching people helping them training
them by coming from a place of
compassion
not a place of wanting to make people do
what they should and made building Trust
be one of the most important things and
that only when they ask for advice or
help did I give it and more people
started asking for my advice that was
the cool thing
that was the really cool part
as more people actually started asking
for my advice and so I could give it
from a from that lens because I went
through the right process
okay
there's another really cool book that I
recommend for everybody
it's called everybody communicates
few connect everyone communicates if you
connect
by John Maxwell what the most effective
people do differ
and this is about what leaders do it's
not about power or popularity or what
about making people
around you feel heard comfortable
and understood
and when you can do that for people you
really take things to the next level
you really allow opportunities to
connect with people and to create space
for lasting change to occur
okay so I hope this has encouraged you I
hope that this has helped you again if
you're just listening to this podcast
for the first time please subscribe
please share it with somebody we do
events every single month to help
coaches trainers mentors authors
speakers get more clients get more leads
or if they're just starting out how to
find their Niche how to figure out how
to create the perfect offer in their
business and I walk you through how to
do that to scale your business to six
seven and eight figures we got like my
client Joshua Giles over 150 000 in one
month just a month ago my client Rick
Pino over a million dollars in one month
with his coaching my client Nathan
Fisher 12 000 a month
and I can help you as well
we build a multiple six-figure close to
seven figure passive income for
ourselves and our business
and I can show you how to do the same if
you're a coach if you're a trainer if
you're a mentor
that's what this podcast is for that's
what my YouTube channel is for
check out over my website
jeremicarkowski.com win one of our next
upcoming Live Events are that we're
doing online we do them over Zoom to
help coach you to raise you up and to
train you and get on the waiting list
for our group coaching program this is
the flagship program that I have where
you get access to all of my courses all
of the training and you get access to me
in an environment with people that are
working on growing their business every
single day
most of the time we're on a waiting list
pretty long waiting list but you'll be
the first to know when it opens back up
again by getting on that all right
we'll talk soon everybody grow your life
and have a good one